現時。
and to provide for related matters.
for privately offered funds.
子代續條例草案交由內務委員會處理。
我會講述有關《香港國安法》的審議過程。
係給分profits tax exemption under Chapter 112。
publicly offered funds，whether they are onshore or offshore funds。
The object of the bill is to amend the Inland Revenue Ordinance, Cap 112.
條例草案委員會主席梁繼昌議員先就委員會報告向本會發言。梁繼昌議員。
only offshore private offered funds and offshore private equity funds enjoy profits tax exemption.
本會恢復二零一八年税務豁免基金繳付利得税修訂條例草案嘅二讀辯論。
this tax disparity is not considered conducive to the further development of Hong Kong's asset and wealth management industry.
岸上私有化基金，with the exception of open-ended fund companies，do not enjoy profits tax exemption.
to allow profits tax exemption for certain funds, whether or not the central management and control of the funds is exercised in Hong Kong.
Acting President, in my capacity as Chairman of the Bills Committee on Inland Revenue Proviso Tax Exemption for Funds Amendment Bill 2018.
for the purpose of the bill, publicly offered fund refers to mutual fund, unit trust or similar investment scheme that is authorised as a collective investment scheme under section 104 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance.
the bills committee supports the bill and the objectives it seeks to achieve.
因為它會 disincentivise funds to dock missile or be managed in Hong Kong.
to further consolidate Hong Kong's competitive edge in the manufacturing and management of funds.
and to avoid being put on the European Union's list of non-cooperative jurisdictions for tax purposes.
成員們已討論過，是否一個基金會成為不資格申請税額豁免的基金。
我會 now highlight the major issues and concerns expressed by the Bills Committee in the course of its deliberation.
如果它投資在一家直接參與這些上市商業活動的公司。
The bill provides that a fund does not include a business undertaking that directly engages in certain commercial activities listed in the bill.
this may not meet the latest base erosion and profit shifting standard of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.
and to adjust certain tax treatment for funds, so that Hong Kong remains competitive in the face of increasing regional and international competition.
Furthermore, the European Union has identified Hong Kong's tax regimes for offshore funds to be problematic on account of their ring fencing features.
referring to the current situation that certain onshore privately offered funds cannot enjoy profits tax exemption that applies to their offshore counterparts.
一 fund， therefore， can be in the legal form of， for example， a partnership， a limited partnership， unit trust， an open-ended fund company， mutual fund corporation， or contractual arrangement。
The administration purposes proposes to introduce amendments to CAPTURE One One Two, to remove ring fencing tax features for fund entities under the existing tax regimes.
成員們已討論了基金的定義在法案中，並指出基金涵蓋了合同安排的概念，以及民事法管轄區的法律安排。
The bill seeks to add a new section to define fund, and provides for the conditions by which any arrangement that meets this new definition would be eligible for profits tax exemption.
如果它投資在一個私營公司。
which engages in those listed commercial activities.
even if a fund is taxed on its non-qualifying transactions.
In respect of the income derived from his investment activities.
一open ended fund company exempt from profits tax.
If at all times during the basis period for a year of assessment.
at present, under Section Twenty Eight H of Chapter One and Two.
and the fund may still qualify for profits tax exemption under the bill.
and would therefore unlikely to be able to qualify for tax exemption.
行政已經解釋過，一個商業或工業用途的企業。
The administration has clarified that it would be part of the normal operation of a fund.
It is a resident person and is non-closely held, as defined in Section Twenty A I.
The purpose of this non-closely held condition is to ensure that an open-ended fund company.
and carries out commercial or industrial transactions would unlikely to be able to satisfy the definition of fund under the bill.
成員有查詢，Whether a company which undertakes both commercial and investment activities would claim profits tax exemption.
the bills committee notes that there will be no tainting effect in the bill, so that the tax exempt profits of the fund will not be tainted.
enjoying tax exemption.
will be replaced by clause five of the bill.
and they have queried how the situations.
and to prevent an individual or corporate investor.
是 not owned by a handful of individuals or corporate investors only.
however， members are aware that sections 28H and 28I。
as those were the other funds, so that there would be a level playing field for funds operating in Hong Kong.
abuse the tax exemption by repackaging as business as an open-ended fund company.
或 be a qualified investment fund， in order to be eligible for profits tax exemption under the bill.
作為開放ended fund companies， are already subject to stringent regulation of the Securities and Futures Commission.
That the two sections seek to prevent would be handled if the non-closely fund condition is not reinstated elsewhere in the bill.
行政機構認為，他們應該繼續享受股息税豁免，於更廣泛的交易範疇。
行政已經解釋過，開設基金公司的條件，要符合税收優惠，基本上應該是相同的。
All funds, including open-ended fund companies, are required to engage a specified person to arrange or carry out its transactions in Hong Kong.
The administration has informed the Bills Committee that open-ended fund companies are regulated by the Securities and Futures Commission, and at least ninety per cent of their investments are required to be securities or related products.
Members also note that, unlike other funds, an open-ended fund company is eligible for profits tax exemption, whether or not the assets in transactions are specified in the proposed Schedule 16C of the bill.
will still be taxable.
The profits arising therefrom.
行政維持，那，它會是困難。
或持有such assets that are utilised to generate income.
行政已經解釋過，作為一個原則。
as the operations of each open-ended company differ.
and appears not appropriate to specify such circumstances in the bill.
in such class of assets, or utilises such assets to generate income.
如果它 engages in direct trading or direct business undertaking in Hong Kong,
議會委員會已討論過如何發展反避税措施，以及它們在實務中的運作。
成員 have discussed whether the bill should specify the circumstances under which an open-ended fund company.
The profits of a fund arising from direct trading or direct business undertaking should be chargeable to profits tax.
而一間開放型基金公司，可能享有profits tax exemption on transactions in assets of a non-schedule sixteen C class under the bill.
會被視為進行直接貿易或直接業務承諾在香港的資產，以非排定16C類別，或持有該等資產以獲取收入。
The administration indicates that, after the bill is passed, the Internal Revenue Department will issue a departmental interpretation and practice note, which will cover the interpretation and practice relating to the bill as a whole.
The bill provides that an open-ended fund company would not be entitled to profits tax exemption if it carries on direct trading or direct business undertaking in Hong Kong in assets of a class that is not specified in the proposed Schedule sixteen C of the bill.
In particular.
Over the private company's assets.
The objectives of these measures.
As the price of immovable property fluctuates over time.
If the latter's immovable property exceeds ten percent of its assets.
under the bill, a fund would be taxed on its profits arising from investment in private company.
the bills committee supports the resumption of the second reading debate on the bill at the council meeting today.
are to discourage funds from investing excessively in the local immovable property market.
成員們有查詢，如何基金的資格，對於税額豁免可能受到影響。
The eligibility would be assessed according to the proportion of the immovable property's value.
to encourage funds to focus on the long-term prospects of the invested private companies.
行政已經也解釋過，這些採用的各種測試並非新嘅。
成員們已考慮過一宗情況，即係一基金投資於一間私營公司，該公司持有某啲資產係不動產。
The administration has explained that a snapshot of the private company's assets would be taken when the fund makes a transaction in that private company.
and to reduce the risk of tax abuse by engaging in trading activities through sales of shares in private companies.
They are either modelled on the existing profits tax exemption regime for open-ended fund companies, or are developed have regard to the information gathered from the private equity fund sector in the earlier consultation exercises.
alot of practitioners.
The main pusher of this.
或the purpose they serve.
now，more than ten years have now passed。
You know, proposed bill is mainly coming from EU.
quite beneficial regarding this bill.
But in in in fact, I think there are four things which are.
The only reason I can see, apart from the lobbying effort of the funds industry as a whole,
No amendment to the bill will be proposed by the Bills Committee.
And now，ridiculously，I，think，very，unfortunately，why，did，the，government，do，this，in，such，a，short，time？
Edwin，Chairman，here is my own view on the Inland Revenue Profits Tax Exemption for Funds Amendment Bill 2018.
now this is in fact a very landmark legislation which would be welcomed by the funds industry in Hong Kong in general.
工業 players have been lobbying the government to relax this regime in order that you know to increase the fund activities in Hong Kong and to benefit the fund management industry as a whole.
now first of all, I think we should note that the definition fund has been expanded to capture different kinds of bona fide funds and operations, regardless of their structure, size.
In fact, since the profits tax exemption regime for offshore funds, meaning those funds, qualified funds with the central management and controlled outside Hong Kong, were given the exemption from profits tax.
A fund in the context of this bill, acting president, can be in the legal form of unit trust partnership, limited partnership, open ended fund company, mutual fund corporation, or even contractual arrangement, which is very common in civil law jurisdiction.
啊！
and if.
馬修斯。
to avoid.
In fact, when
Bill has done is to expand the definition.
invest in immovable property.
Of course， there is also other anti-avoidance。
It is very likely that it fails to qualify as a fund.
那 entity，那 particular legal entity is carrying such a trade or business.
The other second significance of this bill is that.
and of course these private companies, they are allowed to carry on trade or business.
Of course, in order to qualify as a fund, a fund of course undertakes investment. The fund cannot be carrying on a trade or business.
它 allows the fund to invest in private companies, both private companies outside Hong Kong and private companies established inside Hong Kong.
speculation excessive speculation in real estate in immovable property situated in Hong Kong, so there is a minimum a maximum threshold of 10% the valuation of the company taken together, if they have
The administration is drafting was drafting this bill. It definitely has taken into consideration the definition of a collective investment scheme, which is defined in the Securities and Futures Ordinance in Part One, Schedule One of that piece of legislation. Now, this is one thing which the
ineligible assets。
Now, I would urge.
It has just allowed.
and a final.
嗯，The tinting effect。
significance of this bill is that.
在過去，如果基金投資在某
那係第二、第三，real significance of this bill.
一個 ineligible fund is investing in a private company in Hong Kong.
can give some highlight and rationale of know what what this bill is all about.
now，however，this bill has compartmentalised the eligible part and the non-eligible part.
will get taxed. The other part of the fund will still, if other conditions are qualified, be able to get the profits tax exemption.
The whole fund will be tainted, and the profits tax previously given to this fund will be forfeited. The whole fund will not be eligible.
The value of those properties cannot, those immovable properties, I mean, cannot exceed a 10% threshold, and that is one of the criteria when.
My honourable colleagues, to support this bill, although it sounds very technical, it sounds very you know convoluted, the whole bill. But I hope my very brief explanation of what the bill does.
If a fund, for example, has invested in a private company and that private company holds immovable property which has exceeded the threshold, then only the profits deriving from those ineligible investment—that is, the private company.
Now.
羅。
As the number one.
asset management centre Asia。
and，as at today。
Between the years two, one, three, one, four.
will further enhance our.
唔 necess to say， the passage of this bill。
And will generate more business, and will generate more.
has risen by 62% in those five years.
The number of funds authorised by SFC.
In Hong Kong, and that is a very encouraging figure.
the funds just look at the funds authorised by the Securities and Futures Commission alone.
as we all know, Hong Kong is an important international financial centre. In fact, if you look at some figures,
to to years 2017, 2018, and within a time span of just five years.
We got 2,799 SFC authorised collective investment schemes.
Now, of course.
quality employment。
underestimate this effect.
investment into private companies.
Apart from securing funding.
of untapped， you know。
this bill also encourages.
但，more importantly， I must say.
and this is very important, and we should not.
from these venture funds, private equity funds, whatever you call them.
第三個 reason 為我哋應該支持呢個法案，和，喺事實。
funding from these funds will be a major source.
for people supporting the funds industry, the administrators, the bookrunners, the professionals.
from the stock exchange, maybe they're too too small, without track record, maybe they don't want to go public.
new startups, companies involving in fintech, high tech, whatever kind of technology they would like to do, they need money, they need funding.
income for these companies located in Hong Kong, these private companies can now locate in Hong Kong, can now do the R and D. They also benefit from the R and D no super deduction, and now they have the source of funding.
Now.
which meets.
In fact, I have.
國際上，有個叫
The business community and the
In Hong Kong, and I have to say this. I have to tell the business community.
立法會制度， in particular a tax legislative regime.
我有工作，非常 hard 去 secure 一個早 passage of 這 bill，是那。
differs the treatment between onshore and offshore operations.
And Hong Kong is not a tax haven. We have the most stringent, you know, regulation.
however，I think we should not be complacent because there are quite a few things which the government has failed to deliver.
regulators in EU is not quite happy that you know is not is not happy that our
The financial regulators in the EU have to tell the tax authorities in the EU, we have done it. We have done it properly, quickly, effectively and efficiently.
and if we are not going to change the law to give a level playing field between onshore and offshore operation in respect of the funds alone.
The international standard, and we are still moving forward, and we will retain the number one place in asset management as a, also in Asia and hopefully later a number one asset management centre of the world.
There is a very high risk that EU may somehow one day trying to do something to Hong Kong and to enlist Hong Kong as a not very you know transparent or competitive tax regime and maybe putting us on a kind of watch list and this unwelcoming news if they do so.
喺幾分鐘後。
我 must， you know。
and of course the government has been telling.
We should be told what the economic effects are if there's.
所以， altogether， by the end of this day， I hope。
We have dealt with two tax legislations, and we're going to do another one.
但我們沒有見到太多具體的證據或數據。
We have given a lot of incentives to various sectors of business of the economy.
We are pushed through 12 pieces of legislation, which are all tax related.
and since the beginning of this year, 2019， is just two two two months。
to tell us what kind of economic benefits these legislations have brought us.
make a small statistics in the past one year during 2018 there are nine tax related bills which have been passed nine.
to report to the financial affairs panel on a regular basis of the performance of these various financial sectors once these bills have passed, or else.
tell you the truth that many of these bills, if not all, could be wasted. Your effort would be wasted. The effort of all our colleagues in vetting the bills would be wasted.
ask that yes it would it would be beneficial to the economy it would be beneficial to employment but no such figures were ever given to us and then I would urge the government.
We need to be told what are the economic benefits. We want to see some statistics. We want to see, for example, like the employment figure. For example, like you know how many funds have established things like that.
no economic effects。
and secondly, I think.
and research.
on how you know carry interest.
should come down to a very serious study.
Okay，back to the private equity business。
must be finalised and.
formalised as a legislation, and we need that urgently.
company used by a lot of you know Americans.
The Limited Partnership Law, as a collective investment structure.
this could be due to two reasons. One, you are not promoting.
The bureau and the inland revenue department has as a whole.
you know the incentive enough or two the incentive given is too little too late then you must change the law.
Are we doing good? Are we doing okay? After this bill, I don't think so. There are a few more things that you should consider pushing forward quickly. One.
I mean the limited partnership for collective investment purposes, and not the limited partnership for professional firms. So, as a very popular investment vehicle.
I think on many occasions, many of my colleagues, including my colleague Dennis Kwok, has been telling the government that you have to push through the legislation for the establishment of limited partnership in Hong Kong.
蔡主席。
should be taxed.
I think.
although we got so many other advantages.
有有冇其他議員想發言？
would not choose Hong Kong, would avoid Hong Kong in the long run.
can galvanise the support of the whole house. Thank you.
你 have to devise a clear cut way.
要deal with carried interest，你cannot just hide yourself under the sand。
Thanking Chairman, President, that is my speech on the bill, and I hope this bill.
如果冇，我請局長答辯，之後辯論即告結束。財經事務及庫務局局長。
and treat, you know, you know these, you know, accrued carried interest on a case by case basis.
which is a very common, you know, incentive arrangement for private equity funds.
我哋建議嘅税務措施嘅支持，以及喺過程裏邊提及提出一啲有意意誒有非常有用嘅意見。
because if we do not have a consistent and clear policy, let alone a piece of legislation, many of these private equity funds
我感謝法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員同埋其他委員，以及立法會秘書處同埋法律顧問嘅努力，令到二零一八年税務豁免基金繳付利得税修訂條例草案呢個審議工作係得以順利完成。我亦都感謝業界對我。
於迴避税嘅條文，以防止漏税。
誒包括第一相關實體係需要符合基金嘅定義。
實外基金嚟到香港註冊同埋喺香港管理，係不利香港資產同埋財富管理業嘅進一步發展。
特定目的實體嘅層面嘅税項豁免，將係會按基金持有嘅呢一個實體嘅權益百分率而定。
另外一方面，即係可以為喺在香港營辦嘅在岸基金同埋離岸基金，係製造公平嘅競爭環境。
要剔除歐盟對香港適用於以私人形式發售離岸基金呢個税務安排存在分隔措施嘅疑慮。
合資格交易而係受到影響，我哋亦都建議，如果基金透過成立特定目的實體持有同埋管理佢哋喺私人公司所作嘅投資。
第二基金嘅交易係需要由獲證監會發牌嘅發團喺香港安排或者進行，或者基金係屬於符合資格嘅基金。
第二條例草案針對以私人形式發售嘅基金，只要佢哋喺香港營辦並且符合若干條件，無論佢哋係喺在岸或者係離岸，以及佢嘅結構、規模或者目的，都係可以享有利得税豁免。呢一方面係。
根據現行嘅税制，喺以私人形式發售嘅基金中間，只有離岸基金同埋在岸開放式基金型嘅公司係享有利得税豁免，其他在岸基金不能夠同樣噉樣享有利得税嘅豁免。喺基金投資層面方面，
税務條例目前定明，以私人形式發售嘅離岸基金，如果要享有呢個税項豁免，佢哋可以投資喺在海外成立嘅私人公司，但係佢哋不可以投資喺本地嘅私人公司。上述嘅不同嘅税務待遇，或者會。
就此，我哋制定咗條例草案喺税務條例中間加入咗獨立成章嘅修訂條文，畀所有喺香港營辦嘅在岸基金同埋離岸基金，只要符合若干條件，都可以享有同樣嘅利得税豁免嘅安排。需要符合嘅條件。
會唔會現在？
反對嘅請舉手。
二零一八年税務豁免基金繳付利得税修訂條例草案。
我認為議題獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係二零一八年税務豁免基金繳付利得税修訂條例草案，予以議讀。贊成嘅請舉手。
條例草案已經得到法案委員會嘅支持，我懇請本會預議通過，畀呢個税務擴面安排可以喺今年四月開始實施。代主席，我緊止陳詞。
由於境外基金投資喺本地私人公司嘅税務安排，亦都已經移除，本地初創企業亦都應該會因為有機會成為基金嘅投資對象而受惠。
而符合資格嘅基金係需要有最少五名嘅投資者，並且需要符合關於資本認繳總額同埋發放淨收益嘅相關要求。以及第三，基於投資喺指明資產嘅利潤可以獲得利得税豁免，呢一啲啊包括基金通常。
常會投資嘅證券同埋其他類別嘅金融產品。此外，基金投資喺本地同埋海外私人嘅公司都可以享有離得税豁免。此外，我哋建議基金可以享税項豁免嘅利潤，唔會因為其他嘅需要繳税嘅非合。
為咗減低避税嘅風險，我哋亦都會引入咗防止濫用嘅措施，包括對基金喺私人公司嘅投資嘅不動產持有期同埋短期資產作出一啲規限或者要求。此外，我哋亦都喺條例草案裏邊保留咗基金嘅防止於。
法案委員會曾經就基金嘅含義、防止濫用嘅措施呢啲實際操作、開放式基金型公司日後嘅税務安排、特定目的實體嘅税務安排等技術嘅細節係進行咗討論。我哋已經就各項嘅事宜向委員會作出詳細嘅解釋，委員會。
佢並冇進一步嘅問題。代主席，我哋認為條例草案將會有助加強香港喺製造同埋管理基金方面嘅競爭優勢，亦都可以帶動其他相關專業服務嘅需求，促進香港整體金融服務業進一步嘅發展。此外，